Samuel Damashek

Contact

Cell: 571-358-2032

e-mail:

samuel.damashek@invincea.com

6315 Tisbury Dr, Burke, VA 22015

Profile

I am a highly driven high-school student at the Thomas Jefferson High School for Science and Technology interested in a career in computer security. My self-taught skills in computer programming and Linux systems administration have been honed through real-world experience in internships and volunteer activities.

Key Skills

Proficent in:

Linux systems administration and security concepts

virtualization concepts and products, including KVM, Libvirt, QEMU, and XenServer.

Python and C programming languages

Django and Flask Python web frameworks.

deployment and management of Apache and Nginx webservers.

common network structure and network management using Cisco IOS and HP Procurve switches. Familiarity with:

web languages (HTML/CSS/JS) and Java.

common cryptographic standards (RSA, AES, MD5/SHA1/SHA2) and implementations (GnuPG, SSL).

Education

2013 to 2017 Thomas Jefferson High School for Science and Technology, Alexandria, VA

Work Experience

Invincea Labs, LLC

June 2015 - September 2015

Research Intern, Computer Network Operations

- Developed an Intrusion Prevention System fingerprint tool using Python and Scapy
 - Researched rule processing differences between different Intrusion Prevention Systems, including Snort and Suricata, and reported on findings
- Assisted in implementation of long-term infrastructure projects
 - o Helped roll out OpenLDAP directory for user management and authentication

Thomas Jefferson High School for Science and Technology

September 2013 - present

Co-lead of Infrastructure, Student Systems Administrator Program (unpaid) September 2014 - present

- Manage student user accounts using Kerberos for authentication and OpenLDAP for directory storage
- Administer KVM virtualization using Libvirt management
- Administer Cisco IOS and HP Procurve switches
- Helped deploy Salt configuration management system on school servers
- Coded a root password management system using Python and PGP/GnuPG
- Developed and assisted in the implementation of a school-wide SSL certificate authority

Binary Group

May 2012 - September 2012

Volunteer Intern

 Assisted with the design, development, and testing of a mobile application developed to help caseworkers coordinate care for homeless veterans

Professional Activities and Achievements

Awards

- First place (team), Metropolis Cyber Skyline at University of Maryland (2015)
- Sixth place (team), PicoCTF 2014 by Carnegie Mellon University
- First place (team), MITRE STEM CTF 2014 College Division
- Volunteer Gold Star Award from Fairfax County Department of Neighborhood and Community Services (2014)
- First place (team), Booz Allen Hamilton Data Science Bowl (2013)
- First place (team), MITRE STEM CTF 2013